Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Workshop for beginners Burwood Ashram, Sydney (Australia)
對霎哈嘉瑜伽士的講話 初學者工作坊 1983年3月20日 悉尼
The question is: People even before Realization
假使有些人在獲得自覺前
having a certain level of awareness which was.
便已對什麼是自覺有了一定的意識
Are they close to realization and what if they don't even meet you,
那麼 他們是否更接近自覺 萬一他們甚至都不能遇到您該怎麼辦
What is their position?
他們處在一個什麼樣的位置
You have to know that you all have been seekers before
你們必須知道你們曾經全都是求道者
this is not the first time you have been seeking.
你們並不是第一次在求道
So already you have reached a certain state
所以你們已經達到了一定的狀態
where you feel and you are aware that something more
能夠感覺和意識到有更多的事
has to happen to you, you are already ready for that,
必將在你們身上發生 為此你們已做好準備
some of you have really taken birth in this time just for this.
你們中有些人 正是為此而在這個時間出生
So, because I’m not going to talk of your past,
因此 我不想談及你們的過去
past is over now, we have to think of the present.
過去已經完結 我們必須關注當下
One has to know that all of you, get Realization,
你們要知道 你們所有人已得到自覺
some people have certain problems,
有些人 在不同的能量中心
on their different centers as I told you,
有著某些問題 正如我之前所告訴你們的那樣
different types of problems people have.
人們有各種不同的問題
Because of these problems, the Kundalini goes back
由於這些問題 靈量將她的注意力返回
to its attention because Kundalini has to look after your problems.
因為靈量必須照管你們的問題
She’s your mother so she goes there, attends to that problem
她是你們的母親 所以她去到那裡 照管那個問題
and again she rises. But only thing you have to learn,
接著她又再次升起 你們唯一需要學習的
how to make her rise, how to cooperate with her,
是如何使她升起 如何與她協作
how to understand your own problem and give additional help
如何明白你們自己的問題 以及給予額外的幫助
to solve the problem.
來解決這個問題
Now you will be amazed that you just get rid of your
現在你會驚訝於已經擺脫了
false identifications with yourself.
對自己的錯誤認同
You become absolutely detached from that,
你們變得完全抽離
because you start talking in the language of chakras and centers.
因為你們開始使用輪穴 和能量中心的語言來交談
You start saying that this center is bad, that center is bad,
你們開始說 這個能量中心不好 那個能量中心不好
this is not alright Mother, that’s wrong with me,
母親 這裡不妥 我那裡有問題
that is wrong with me, that’s all. You don’t say I’ve cancer,
我那裡有問題 就這樣 你們不會說 我有癌症
you don’t say I’m mad, you don’t say I’m egoistical.
不會說 我瘋了 不會說 我是個自我中心的人
You just say : “Mother this center is not alright,
你們只是說 母親 這個能量中心不妥
that center is not alright.”
那個能量中心不妥
Depending on the quality of your centers, the chakras,
根據你們能量中心的品質
for the energy of God to flow in.
流入人體的通道
Regarding them, you have to be careful, how your chakras are.
就這點而言 你們必須留心你們的輪穴
Are you clean or not?
你們是否清潔
Some of you will find cool breeze flowing alright in the hand,
有些人會在手上感覺到涼風流動
but may be, one chakra is catching.
也可能某個輪穴感染
On one chakra you will feel the heat, or you may feel the numbness,
某個輪穴上你會感覺熱或者麻
you might feel also a kind of a
也可能
– we can say a kind of a tingling on certain fingers.
某些手指有麻刺感
Now wherever there is tingling,
哪裡有麻刺感
you must know there is a kind of a struggle going on
你們必須知道
So you should just try to help your chakras, to awaken them
所以你們只要嘗試幫助你的輪穴 喚醒她
and also must know that every one of you
同時你們必須知道 每一個人
are part and parcel of the whole. You are awakened,
都是整體的一部分 你們已經被喚醒
you are awakened to that part and so you have to be more careful.
你們已經意識到這一點 所以必須更加小心
Because if you suffer from some chakra, I can feel it.
如果你們因為某些輪穴受苦 我能感覺到
But if others, those who are not Realized,
但如果是其他人 那些沒有得到自覺的人
I don’t feel it at all, I’m not bothered,
我根本不會感覺到 我不會被煩擾
There can be any number of devils or anything,
無論有多少邪魔 或其他什麼
doesn’t matter to me.
對我來說無所謂
But if you people, who are Realized souls,
但如果你們 已獲得自覺的人
have a slight problem immediately I know
哪怕只是微小的問題 我會立刻
that you have this problem, my attention is diverted to that.
知道你們有這個問題 我的注意力便轉向它
So you must understand that the attention is all the time there
所以你們必須明白 注意力始終在那裡
to look after you, to give you a better guidance,
照顧你們 給予你們指引
your Spirit is all the time working.
你們的靈每時每刻都在工作
But you must learn how to take the guidance from your Spirit
但你們必須學習如何跟隨靈的指引
that’s the main point; so nobody is lower or higher as he said.
這是重點 所以 並沒有哪個人 像他自己所說的那樣 比其他人更差或者更好
I’ve seen some people who were declared as
我曾經見到被稱為酒鬼之類的人
[with that], they are perfect people, not only, but very good Sahaja Yogis.
他們成了非常棒的人 甚至是非常好的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
So, you see, all these clouds have come on the sky of your being
所以 你們看 此生中有些烏雲遮蓋了
in this life time, doesn’t matter, makes no difference,
你們的天空 沒關係 沒有分別
but your past is great, that shows.
你們的過往很偉大 能看得出來
So you don’t have to worry as to how far you are where you are,
你不必擔心走了多遠 你在哪裡
there’s no degree or anything to measure it.
沒有什麼學位 或其它什麼東西可以用來衡量它
They must be all aware already, otherwise you would not come to me,
你們必定已經有這種意識 否則不會一開始就來找我
first of all. And to get Realization itself, is very big.
獲得自覺 這本身就很了不起
Now there’s a very good seeker I know of, who came to me,
我知道 有一個非常好的求道者 來到我的面前
and he got his Realization but he did not feel it on his hand,
獲得自覺 但是他手上沒有感覺
because he has a very bad Vishuddhi.
因為他喉輪不好
And with a bad Vishuddhi chakra,
喉輪不好
you may not feel it in your hand, doesn’t matter,
在手上可能會感覺不到 沒有關係
but you’ll feel peaceful, you’ll feel joyful.
但你們會感受到平安和喜樂
And you can feel it on top of your head, or others can feel it.
你們也能在頭頂上感覺到 或者其他人能感覺到
Gradually your fingers will start improving
漸漸地你們的手指開始改善
and they will give you better results.
會帶給你們更好的感知
For example, people who do hard work with their hands,
比如 用手辛勤勞作的人
also their fingers can be numbed,
他們的手指也會變得麻木
so we have to use certain methods, like looking after our hands.
因此我們必須用一些特定的方法 照顧我們的雙手
This body now is a temple of God
現在 這個身體是神的聖殿
so we have to look after it in a way, respectfully,
所以我們必須帶著尊重去照顧它
not for the way the – you see, the prostitutes,
而不要象妓女那樣
when they want to sell their body they look after their body.
為了出賣身體而去照顧它
No, but respect, with respect to our body.
不是那樣 而是要尊重 給予我們的身體以尊重
We have to look after ourselves in a way
我們必須以恰當的方式照顧自己
that we should keep good health.
以使我們保持健康
And to keep good health in Sahaja Yoga,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽中
there are thousand and one things, which you have to know,
要保持身體健康有許多種方法 你們必須知道
which is very easy to understand,
它們很容易理解
and which will be told to you for no price at all, nothing.
而且完全不收費
It is the Divine that is anxious that you should get it,
那是神聖的大能 祂渴望你們得到祂
that you should settle down, that you should enjoy.
你們應當安頓下來 你們應該享受
So you don’t have to be so anxious about it.
所以對此你們沒必要如此擔憂
These anxieties must be given up, just try to understand your centers.
必須放棄這些擔憂 只是嘗試瞭解你們的能量中心
Now many of you who did feel the cool breeze.
現在你們許多人確實感受到了涼風
But maybe, after some time, you may lose it, doesn’t matter.
但是一段時間後 你們可能會失去它 沒關係
You’ll go up and down, like that, doesn’t matter.
你們會像那樣上下起伏 沒有關係
It does not mean that you’ve lost it, not at all.
那並不意味著你們失去了它 不是
Now supposing you try a method, a simple method,
現在 比如你們嘗試一種方法 一種簡單的方法
that you first put your left hand towards my photograph
首先將你們的左手朝向照片
– just now you can try –
現在就可以試試
and right hand on the Mother Earth, let’s see.
右手放在大地母親之上 讓我們看看
Right hand on the Mother Earth,
右手按著大地母親
that’s why I wanted to have it in the open,
這就是為什麼起初 我想在戶外來做這個工作坊
but doesn’t matter now, this rain is good for you for the farmers,
不過現在也沒關係 這場雨對你們和對農民都是很好的
So now put your left hand like this,
那麼 現在把你們的左手像這樣放著
and right hand – those who are sitting can put up like that
右手 坐著的人 可以把右手像這樣舉起來
Like this. Back. Right hand like this, right. Not left, right.
像這樣 向後 對 右手像這樣 不是左手 右手
[Yogi] …the ground. No like this.
放在地上 不是這樣
Back. Yes, right hand.
向後 是的 右手
Now what we are doing, the left hand side power,
現在我們正在做的 左邊的力量
is the emotional power.
是情感的力量
Now if you have an emotional problem
現在假如你們有一個情感問題
– say, somebody has been taking drugs,
比如說 有人吸毒
he’s a left sided person.
那麼他是個左脈的人
Some drugs are, LSD and all that right-sided,
有些毒品是中樞神經幻覺劑 是偏右的
but most of the drugs take you to the left side.
但大多數毒品把你們帶向左邊
Gurus are left sided part.
導師問題是左邊的問題
Most of these problems are mental problems, are left sided problems.
大多數這類問題屬於精神問題 是左脈問題
But the problem of the intellectuals is right sided,
但是腦力勞動者的問題是右脈的
futuristic people is right sided.
未來取向的人偏右脈
People who are running the rat race are right sided,
忙得團團轉的人是右脈的
you see, that kind of over activity, that kind of things.
你們看 他們過度活躍 是那種狀態
On the contrary, those who have taken to drugs are left sided.
相反 那些吸毒的人偏向左脈
So first try with the left, let’s see.
所以我們先從左脈開始
Now put your right hand on the Mother Earth.
現在把你們的右手按在大地母親上
Put your right hand on the Mother Earth.
將你們的右手放在大地母親身上
Now, put your left hand towards me.
現在 把你們的左手朝向我
Gradually, you’ll find it will start flowing in you left hand.
慢慢地你會發現 它開始在你的左手流動
Is it flowing?
在流動嗎
Put your right hand on the Mother Earth,
把你們的右手按在大地母親上
because the Mother Earth takes away ;
因為大地母親會帶走負面
you see, you are just earthing it, put it on it,
看 你們只是放在大地上 放在上面
touching it, touch, touch it, you see, you are earthing yourself,
觸碰她 觸碰她 你們看 你們在與大地聯接
is a very simple thing.
這是十分簡單的事
Now left sided problems easily go to Mother Earth,
現在左脈的問題 輕易地流入大地母親
it’s true, but the best is to have a light.
是真的 但最好有光
Now, say, if you have a candle,
如果你們有一支蠟燭
candle is the best, for left sided problems,
蠟燭對左脈問題是最好的
candle is the best thing to take it.
蠟燭是可以帶走左脈的問題的好東西
Because left sided problems, we can say, are cold problems,
因為左脈的問題 可以說是因為冷
or problems which arise from coldness.
或者說是由冷而產生的問題
You see, a person who becomes inactive.
你看 一個人變得怠惰
Now see.
現在
You just put your left hand towards me like this
你們只要把左手朝向我 像這樣
and right hand towards a candle.
右手朝向蠟燭
the candle starts burning “tac”and drop like that
蠟燭會 噗噗 地燃燒和滴蠟
and sometimes it creates such black smoke that,
有時會產生黑煙
if it is next to a wall, you might find the all wall becoming black.
如果靠著牆 你會發現整面牆變黑
It’s very interesting to see how the candle reacts,
觀察蠟燭怎麼反應非常有趣
but you must have a photograph in front.
但是你們必須在前面放一張照片
And there should be a candle in front of the photograph
照片前要放一支蠟燭
and one candle like this to take it out.
一支像這樣的蠟燭 可以把它清除掉
Right, now, see better?
好了 現在看看好點嗎
Alright?
好了吧
You’ll feel it’s going down. You’ll feel from your head, you’ll feel,
你們會感到它往下走 你們從頭上感覺到
Better now? Like this. Put the hand like that, back side,
現在好點了嗎 像這樣 手像那樣放 背面
not towards me, like that yes, yes. Now. Hum.
不是朝著我 像那樣 對的 對的
Now put left hand, if you ‘re sitting on the ground,
現在 如果你們是坐在地上
it’s better to put towards me, left hand.
那你們最好是把左手朝向我 左手
It’s coming, it’s going, it’s working.
它來了 走了 它在工作
It’s like the energy, you see, that is coming through the photograph,
你看 它好像能量一樣 從照片裡出來
it’s pushing it down towards the light,
正在往下沉 朝著燭光
and the light burns it off : light gets awakened, by you.
那燭光把它燒掉了 燭光通過你們被喚醒
It’s surprising but it does.
這很神奇 但這是真的
It’s better now? See. We work out, we feel it.
現在好點了嗎 看 我們成功了 我們能感受到它
You will feel it yourself, there is nothing to certify.
你自己就可以感覺到 沒有什麼是需要證明的
You will feel yourself. Put your left hand towards me,
你可以自己感覺它 把你們的左手朝向我
left hand towards me like this, yes.
左手像這樣朝向我 對的
You all will feel it yourself.
你自己就能感受到它
Now people who have been to gurus,
現在那些跟過各種導師的人
who have sort of schizophrenic attitude,
有某種精神分裂的人
who are moody people, frantic, fits, they get all sorts of these,
喜怒無常的 狂亂的 痙攣的人 所有這些類型的人
to extreme to the least you see, who are emotional,
所有這些極端的 罕見的類型 你們看 他們是情緒化的
some women who cry too much, hysterics, all those things
有些女士哭得太多 歇斯底里 所有這些事
can be controlled by this simple method
都可以通過這個簡單的方法來控制
of putting left hand towards the photograph
只要將左手朝向照片
and right hand towards a candle.
右手朝向蠟燭
See, it’s working out?
看是不是在改善
You’ll feel the movement in your head you’ll feel. [Yogi] Yes.
你可以感覺到它在頭腦中移動
Feeling it now. No?
現在感覺到了嗎 沒有
[Yogi] So, it’s not there.
它不在那裡
Now with the right hand up,
現在來說右脈
those who are running the rat race,
那些忙得團團轉的人
you see big people who think they must earn money and all,
你們看到的那些大人物 他們認為必須賺大錢
they are running in the politics and
在政治裡競爭等等
all that kind of a – another madness they have. You see,
他們有另一種瘋狂的行為
that’s also a kind of madness, you see. [Shri Mataji laughs]
你們看那是另一種瘋狂
So for such people who are having a high blood pressure because of that,
所以對於這類因此而有高血壓的人
they will have diabetes, they’ll have liver trouble.
他們會患糖尿病 肝臟出問題
Now even for any organ, you see, any organ you take, say heart,
現在 任何器官 你們看任何器官 比如說心臟
in Sahaja Yoga we have for every organ, two types of nature.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽裡對於所有的器官 都有兩種特性
One is the one that is lethargic and another that is overactive.
一種是昏沉怠惰 另一種是過度活躍
So supposing you are an overactive person,
因此 假設你是一個過度活躍的人
then if you are an overactive person,
那麼如果你過度活躍
you are studying very hard
你會非常努力地讀書
or thinking about the future or planning something,
或想著未來 或者計畫一些事
then, you have a heart which is overactive.
那麼 你會有過度活躍的心臟
Or you have an intestine which is overactive.
或者有過度活躍的腸道
The liver is overactive, the whole system is overactive,
肝臟也過度活躍 整個系統都過於活躍
you’ll have high blood pressure
你會有高血壓
and all the problems of high blood pressure, constipation,
以及由高血壓帶來的所有問題 便秘
all these things go hand in hand in one personality.
所有這些在人體內都是息息相關
Then, another personality could be a lethargic.
然後 另一種情況是昏沉怠惰
A person who has a lethargic heart,
一個人如果有著惰性的心臟
may get a- has to get a bypass or something like that,
則可能要做搭橋手術之類的
because the heart doesn’t pump.
因為心臟不能泵血
You may have a lethargic intestine, such a person might
你可能會有惰性的腸道 這樣的人
– whatever he eats you see, just goes to the bathroom,
無論吃什麼 都要上洗手間這種
sort of a thing or may be a lethargic liver.
又或者有惰性的肝臟
When you have a lethargic liver then you might get allergies.
當你有一個惰性的肝臟時 有可能會有過敏
Allergies are caused by lethargic liver.
過敏是由惰性的肝臟所造成
But, if you are an overactive person, if you are overactive,
但如果你是一個過度活躍的人 如果你過度活躍
then the same liver which was giving you these allergies,
那麼同樣一個讓你過敏的肝臟
will give you nausea, a feeling of a sickness,
會讓你感覺噁心 不舒服
migraine, and vomiting, emesis.
偏頭痛 上吐下瀉
So there are two types of livers also.
所以有兩種類型的肝臟
We have two types of kidneys,
我們也有兩種腎臟
two types of, everything is two types.
什麼東西都有兩種性質
So if you are a lethargic person, if you have a lethargic problem,
所以 如果你是一個昏沉怠惰的人 如果你有昏沉的問題
then what you have to do is to use the light.
那麼你要做的就是用光
For all the lethargic troubles, best is the light,
對於所有的昏沉問題 最好是用光
to use the light for lethargic troubles, this is left side.
用光來對付昏沉怠惰的問題 這是左邊
And for the right sidedness, you can use the Mother Earth.
那麼 對於右邊 你們可以利用大地母親
Mother Earth is the best or water and salt.
大地母親是最好的 或者水和鹽
So water and salt is very good for people who are suffering
水和鹽 對於那些過度活躍的人是很好的
from an over-activity. Now how do you do it?
過度的活躍 你該怎麼做
It’s good for both, but specially for them.
這個方法對於兩邊都很好 特別是右脈
Like you have to put both the hands, first towards the photograph
首先雙手朝向照片
both the feet in the water, with little salt.
把雙腳放入水裡 水里加一點鹽
Now if you are feeling the vibrations coming in both the hands,
如果你們在雙手上感覺到 同樣多的生命能量
equally the same, it’s alright, you don’t have to worry.
那很好 你們不用擔心
But supposing, one hand is more and one hand is less.
但是假設一隻手感覺多一些 另一隻少一些
The hand that is less has to go before the photograph, always.
要把那只感覺較少的手朝向照片
The hand that is less has to go towards the photograph
那只感覺較少的 要朝向照片
and another one has to go out.
而另一隻手（豎起來朝後） 用來排出負面
And you’ll be amazed, the movement of the thing,
然後你會驚訝地發現它的移動
you will feel within yourself these balloons will be moving like that.
在你自己內在會感覺到[頭部自我和超我] 的氣球會像那樣[從右往左 從左往右]移動
And you can feel it, that something is moving in your head,
並且你能感到 有東西在頭裡移動
you are getting relaxed. And gradually, you’ll become a master,
同時你會感覺放鬆 逐漸地 你會成為一個大師
you will know how to handle this body,
你會知道怎麼掌握這個身體
absolutely, you‘ll become a master. And when you become master
完完全全地成為一個大師 當你成為大師
– people have become masters in eight days, in eight days.
有人在八天內成為大師 只用了八天
Once you become a master, then you can handle other bodies also
一旦你們成為大師 你就可以掌握別人的身體
and help other people. It’s as simple as that.
幫助別人 就是那麼簡單
So forget about the past, now the present,
所以忘了過去吧 現在此刻
we have to be in the present.
我們需要處於當下
Is there any other question now?
還有其他的問題嗎
[Yogi] … about mantras…
關於口訣
Mantras, yes. Now, we have got different centers,
口訣 是的 我們有不同的能量中心
and all these centers have got different deities.
所有這些能量中心都有著不同的神祇
As I told you, Lord Jesus Christ is here.,
就如我曾告訴過你們 耶穌基督是在這裡
Moses is here, Krishna is here. We have a chart of that.
摩西在這裡 克裡希那在這裡 我們有一張那樣的圖
We have books which will be given to you.
我們還有一些書會給你們
Now, we have to make, you see-
現在我們要
[Yogi] Excuse me. [Sahaja Yogi brings a big chart]
打擾一下
Yes this is the chart, you see, it’s beautifully done,
對 這是那張圖 你們看 這張圖做得很好
this one is very clear cut.
非常清晰明瞭
Now on different chakras, we have different deities
現在 在不同的輪穴中 我們有不同的神祇
– come forward, you come forward and see, alright?
往前來 你們到前面來看 好嗎
Alright, just let him see. You can pass it on.
好的 給他看看 你們可以傳著看
[Yogi] May be there’s another chart.
好像還有一張圖
Another chart, alright.
還有一張圖 好吧
We have books, you see, why not give them books?
我們有書 為什麼不給他們書
[Yogi] …They can have the other books
他們可以拿別的書
Open the books, you have got the chart in the books. Can you see?
打開書 書裡就有這張圖 看到了嗎
Now gradually you see, we are trying to get a bigger place for you,
你看 慢慢地我們會給大家 找一個更大的地方
and we should really meet in a hall again. When are you going to –
下次我們真的應該在禮堂裡會面 你們什麼時候
Sahaja Yogi :… they can meet here first until we get a hall
在我們找到禮堂之前 他們可以先在這裡聚會
Yes if you want, we might not be able to get but you can meet here.
是的 如果你們願意 我們也可能找不到 但你們可以在這裡聚會
You can always come and find out. Now, what is it?
你們可以隨時來看看 現在 什麼
There are books. Now, I’ll show.
是有些書 現在我就拿給你們
These are small books just meant for the beginner, you see.
這些小冊子正是給初學者看的 你看
Now here, this is all given in short.
在這兒 全都簡潔地描述出來了
Now this is the chart you have to follow
這兒是一張你們需要遵循的圖表
– you can pass it on…
你們可以傳閱一下
Give this to that gentleman also he wanted. Ah, you’ve got.
把它給那位男士 他也想要 哦 你已經拿到了
Gentleman : I got it here.
我拿到了
Oh I see. You also take.
好的 你也拿到了
Now. So the mantras are according to the chakra that is in problem.
口訣是針對有問題的能量中心
Supposing your Nabhi chakra is not alright. Alright?
假定你們的臍輪不妥當
And if you start saying the mantra of this one is no use.
如果你們說這裡的口訣 （Shri Mataji 指額輪） 將不會起作用
So you must know what center is catching, from your fingers.
所以你們必須通過手指知道 哪個能量中心有阻塞
Now you can make out here, in this chart if you see
現在你們可以在這裡辨別 在這張圖中 如果你看向
on this side, we have got written the numbers according to the centers.
這一邊 我們已經標了數字 對應不同的能量中心
On this side, if you see it clearly?
在這一邊 能看得清嗎
Now these are the numbers of the centers, alright?
這些是能量中心對應的數字 對嗎
So then, and also here it is written in this chart,
然後 在這幅圖裡也寫了
what are the different deities.
有哪些神祇
Now, all these deities should be first understood,
現在 首先應瞭解所有這些神祇
where are they, and when you have to say the mantras,
祂們在哪裡 當你們要說口訣的時候
what you have to do is coil it into a proper Sahaja Yoga mantra
你們需要做的是把它放入一個 恰當的霎哈嘉瑜伽口訣
– so have you given that?
這個你給過他們了嗎
[Yogi] It’s not in these books..
不在這些書裡
But they will tell you.
不過他們會告訴你
The pattern has to be like this, which says,
句式應該是這樣的
whatever is the thing is, is woven into the complete
無論什麼 都要編入那個完整的（句式）
- I mean you are to be recommended, isn’t it? Somebody has to say.
我的意思是建議你們 對嗎
So you have to say that
所以你們應說
I am the one who has given you this knowledge.
我就是那個給予你們知識的人
So just you have to use that particular thing
所以你們要使用那個特定的句式
which they will give you, the pattern, which is very simple.
他們會給你們 那個句式非常簡單
And you have to use these names of these deities, different deities
你們必須用這些神祇的名號 用相應的神祇名號
But when you come here, they will tell you, it’s very simple,
你來這裡的時候 他們會告訴你 它是非常簡單的
it’s very simple. But you must know where the chakras are.
非常簡單 但是你們要知道輪穴在哪裡
First of all, you must become sensitive.
首先 你們必須變得敏感
So I would suggest that you must start using olive oil
所以我會建議你們 必須在你們的手指和腳趾上
for your fingers and for your toes, you see,
使用橄欖油 你們看
rub it nicely, make your fingers sensitive.
好好地按摩它 讓你們的手指敏感
Because of various things, our hands have become gross, you see.
因為各種各樣的原因 我們的手變得粗糙
To feel it better, use some nice olive oil, massage it nicely.
要更好的感覺它 用一些好的橄欖油好好地按摩它
And sometimes, if you wear the gloves in the night,
有時候如果晚上你們帶著手套睡
they can soften it also. You must soften, soft hands are better.
也可以軟化它 你們要讓它柔軟 柔軟的手比較好
And the nails should not be very long, not very badly cut,
然後 指甲不要太長 或者剪得很糟糕這樣
So that when you use on others, they should not feel hurt
這樣當你為別人按摩的時候 他們不會被你的指甲傷到
you should not have very –right hand specially –
你們不應該 尤其是右手
because you’ll have to use it like this here,
因為你們需要在這裡用到它
say, you have a Vishudhi chakra,
比如 你有喉輪的問題 [錫呂.瑪塔吉好像在用右手食指給喉輪班丹]
then you’ll have to use your Nabhi chakra like that
然後 像這樣地使用你的臍輪[使用中指]
So what, actually, is the matter with you,
那麼 實際上重點是什麼
is to be first heard. So first you have to understand yourself,
你們要先得到自覺 首先瞭解你自己
what is your problem, what you are suffering from,
你有什麼問題 你有什麼遭遇
and then, how to correct.
然後 怎樣去糾正
If you could find out how to correct it and what is your problem,
如果你們能找出怎樣去糾正 你的問題是什麼
then it is the easiest thing, is to coil a mantra to improve yourself.
然後 最簡單的事就是 找到口訣 改善自己
Alright? It’s very simple.
好吧 這非常簡單
Now you have met me only a day back, I should say,
現在 你們才剛剛見到我一天
but you’ll be amazed the knowledge
但是你會驚訝地發現
that you will have now about yourself, will be tremendous.
你們將要學到的有關自身的知識如此偉大
So first is SelfRealization, means you know yourself.
所以 首先獲得自覺 意味著認識你自己
Once you know yourself, you start knowing others,
一旦認識了你自己 你將開始認識其他
because we are all collectively conscious.
因為我們是集體意識
Those who are Realized souls become aware of others.
那些得到自覺的靈變得能夠覺知他人
So first of all, if you want to see your own vibrations,
所以 首先 如果你們想看看你們自己的生命能量
you have to put yourself into bandhan like this,
你們要像這樣做班丹
as I told you, like this.
我告訴過你們 像這樣
Now, let’s do it.
現在 我們來一起做
Put your left hand towards me.
把你的左手朝向我
[Yogi] Like this towards Shri Mataji…
像這樣朝向錫呂.瑪塔吉
Now, these are your vibrations, whatever it is, now check,
現在 這就是你們的生命能量 不論是什麼 現在去看看 去感受它
Now this is left Nabbhi. Now which one is burning, be careful.
現在 這是左臍輪 現在哪個手指熱呢 仔細些
Pay attention.
注意力放好
Which one?
哪一個
May be he is constipated, is he? Does he get constipation?
可能他有便秘 是不是 他有便秘問題嗎
Yes, it’s the liver, sign of liver, you see and also constipated.
這裡是肝臟 肝臟的代表 （Shri Mataji 伸出右手中指） 你們看便秘也是
So he is more a right sided person,
所以他就是一個偏右的人
because right side is this thing.
因為右邊是這樣
So he has to put left to the right, like this. Alright?
所以他要把左邊移到右邊去 像這樣 好嗎
[Newcomer] I’m just warm [?] and [?]..what could that mean?
我只覺得有點溫熱和黏糊糊的 這代表什麼意思
You have a heart [problem]
你有心臟問題
[Newcomer] It’s allergy [?]
這是過敏
You put your right hand on your heart.
你把右手放在心臟上
Warm? Alright, doesn’t matter, and the other one?
熱 好吧 沒關係 另一隻手呢
Nothing. Alright. So put your left to the right. Left to the right.
什麼感覺也沒有 好吧 把你的左邊移到右邊去 從左邊到右邊
[Yogi] You take it- when She says left to the right,
當祂說從左邊移到右邊
what you’re doing is not just this one,
你們照做就行了 你做的不完全對
put you are actually lifting the left side
你只是在提升左脈
And taking the grace from the right.
從右邊邊獲得能量
And taking the grace, you see, on the right side,
你看這是在右邊獲得能量
because right side is showing nothing.
因為右邊沒有任何感覺
If the right side is showing nothing,
如果右邊沒有感覺
then what you are doing, you are lifting your left
那麼要做什麼呢 是將你們的左邊提升
which is slightly showing and you take up and bring it down,
提升有感覺的左邊
with your right hand. Left to the right.
然後降下 從左到右
[Yogi] If you got problems on the right side,
如果你們右邊有問題
Then it’s the opposite, it’s as simple as that.
然後 再反過來 就這麼簡單
If she’s not- if you are not feeling at all on right hand,
如果她沒有 如果你的右手完全沒有感覺
then you have right hand problem.
那麼你有右邊的問題
You’re not feeling any vibrations, hum?
你沒有感覺到任何生命能量嗎
And left hand, you are feeling what?
左手呢 感覺怎麼樣
[Yogi] Slightly warm on the left side….
她說左邊有些熱
So she has to go from right to left.
所以她需要從右邊到左邊
Just do it yourself now, get into balance
你自己做 取得平衡
that’s the object of what Shri Mataji is saying.
那就是錫呂.瑪塔吉想表達的重點
[Yogini] Can we change hands?
可以換手嗎
Yes you can, you change hands.
可以 你們可以換手
[Yogi] Just to repeat it again, if you have abnormal sensations,
重複再做一遍 如果右手感覺異常
heat or something in your right hand, that means there is a damage
或者有熱氣或其他什麼 說明右邊有損傷
on that side, so you lift the left side
那麼 你要提升左邊
and you bring down the grace inti the right side.
把能量帶到右邊降下
Just do that if you got that problem.
如果你有這樣的問題就這麼做
Right to the left.
提升右邊到左邊
You take your right hand and put it like that.
你們的右手象這麼做
[Yogi] If you got it in the other direction, you change hand as She said,
如果是另外一邊有感覺 就象祂說的換只手做
and you go the other way. It’s as simple as that.
反過來做 就這麼簡單
Until it balances, until it works ou t. Keep doing until it works out.
一直到平衡為止 持續做到感覺有效果為止
Did you come to my program before?
你們以前來過我的講座嗎
No
沒有
That’s why. Just it has started, you see,
這就是原因 它才剛剛開始 你看
you have to get your Realization first of all, alright?
首先你要得到自覺 好嗎
You come here. We’ll have to work it out, first of all,
到這邊來 我們先來獲得自覺
as your Realization has not worked out, that’s why. It just started.
你還沒有得到自覺 所以會這樣 它才剛開始
Hum? Let it work out. If the Realization works out,
我們把它成就出來 只有獲得了自覺
then only you can feel it properly. That’s why.
你們才能夠很好地感覺到它 那就是為什麼
Right side, not at all, so I was wondering why. Are you feeling ?
右邊一點感覺都沒有 我剛才還在想著為什麼 你有感覺嗎
Good. Left hand what are you feeling?
好 左手有什麼感覺
Cool breeze, in the left hand and not on the right. Alright.
左手有涼風 右手沒有 好吧
So what you do is to take left to the right
那麼 從左邊移到右邊
No, with the right hand.
不 用右手
[New Yogini] Oh, yes.
好的
Gradually when you practice you will know. Better now? Good?
漸漸地當你開始練習 你就會知道 現在好些了嗎 好 好的
Good! He’s alright.
好的 他沒問題
Are you alright? How are you feeling?
怎麼樣 你們現在感覺怎麼樣
[Yogi] She’s asking you get heat on the left side or the left hand?
她想問您是身體左邊還是左手變熱
You can get it on left hand or left side, anywhere. Where are you getting?
可能是在左手上或者身體左邊的任何部位 你是哪裡變熱
Yes, you can get it on both the sides. Are you getting on right?
是的 左右兩邊可能都會變熱 你是右邊有熱
Then you put your left to the right.
那麼 從左移到右
No, no, no, left hand towards Me, and right hand like this,
不 不 不 左手朝著我 右手這樣做
Just raise it and bring it down like this. Don’t go back.
直接提升能量 然後像這樣放下 不要倒回去
Both the hands cool?
兩隻手都涼
Look at Me. Left hand to Me, like this
看著我 左手朝向我 像這樣放
and right hand you pick it up, come here and push it down.
用右手將能量提起來 來到這兒 然後放下
She’s alright. You're alright.
她可以了 你沒問題
What about you? Feeling cool breeze in both the hands?
你呢 兩隻手都有涼風嗎
The balance, yes. You start feeling the balance. That’s the best way.
平衡 對的 你開始感覺到平衡了 這是最好的方法
You have a Vishuddhi that way. Doesn’t matter.
你有喉輪的問題 沒關係
You put your left hand at the back of your chakra, here.
把左手放在喉輪背面 這兒
And put your right hand towards Me. Right hand.
右手朝著我 右手
What about you? Are you feeling?
你呢 感覺到了嗎
Nothing? You never felt any cool breeze? Surprising.
沒有 一點涼風也沒感覺到嗎 吃驚
You come from which state? UP!
你從哪個州來的 U.P. (印度北方邦Uttar Pragesh）
[Hindi conversation]
印地語談話
New Sahaja Yogini : How long does that type of things ..?
這種感覺持續多長時間
Split of a second.
一瞬間
New Sahaja Yogini : How long will it last, balancing yourself?
平衡能保持多長時間
[Yogi] How long will the balancing last you?
您自己的平衡能保持多長時間
Last? I mean there is no timing for it.
保持 我的意思是不能為它設定時間
It can last you for ever, but if you are a very wobbly type,
它可以讓你永遠保持 但如果你搖擺不定
it may a little bit drop on, but you have to know how to do it, you see?
它可能會掉下一些 但是你必須知道怎麼去做 對嗎
Now, we can say we are driving a car.
現在 可以說我們正在駕駛一輛車
Now, how long will it last there?
它會持續多久呢
As long as you keep it.
取決於你對於它的保持
You are driving this car, alright?
你們正在駕駛這輛汽車 對嗎
Now, what is it? Are you feeling the balance now?
那麼 怎麼樣 現在感覺到平衡了嗎
[New Yogini] I? Yes.
我嗎 是的
Good, then it’s good.
好的 非常好
[Yogi] When it becomes imbalanced, that’s when you correct it.
當變得不平衡的時候 你們需要去糾正它
[New Yogini] So, just trough the day, you just have to
所以在一天中必須要這樣做嗎
No, no, no, no, no, no. Now, if you’re in balance,
不 不 不 不 不 如果你們是平衡的
there is nothing wrong, it’s alright, perfectly alright.
沒有任何問題 很好 非常的好
[Yogi] Can you get it when you haven’t had the Realization. You mean the balancing?
沒獲得自覺能感覺得到嗎 您指的是平衡嗎
That is the first, that’s the first thing.
那是第一步 是首要的
Otherwise you have not entered into the kingdom of God, isn’t it?
否則你還沒有進入神的國度 對嗎
First thing is to have your Realization and then, now,
首先 你要得到自覺
put your hands towards me.
然後 現在把手朝向我
the more you put your hands to Mother,
因為你越是把手朝向母親
the stronger the vibrations will flow.
就會有更強的能量流入
Take this chance because it has to develop.
抓住這個機會 因為它需要進化
It might be a little uncomfortable, but just keep your hands to Mother.
可能會有一點點的不舒服 但是 請把手朝著母親
You got the cool breeze in your hands, are you feeling?
你們能感覺到你們手上的涼風 感覺到了嗎
Start, close your eyes.
開始了 閉上眼睛
What about you? No.
你呢 沒有
[Yogi] Those who haven’t their Realization, put their hands up please.
那些沒有得到自覺的 請舉手
You come forward. I think best is
你們上前來 我覺得這樣最好
- and the rest of the people and Sahaja Yogis can see. Come along.
這樣其他的霎哈嘉瑜伽士可以看到 來吧
Now these people can be taught by Sahaja Yogis how to give Realization,
現在霎哈嘉瑜伽士 會指導這些人怎樣得到自覺
you are alright, three of you, go ahead. [People move]
你們可以 你們三個 往前來
And the Sahaja Yogis can meet them and talk to them.
然後霎哈嘉瑜伽士可以告訴他們
Sit down, sit down.
坐下 坐下
Just like this. Put your hand.
就像這樣 放你的手
Are you feeling? Do like that with your eyes, do a little bit.
你有感覺嗎 用你的眼睛像那樣做 一點點
Just press them, press your eyes hard, very hard- thrice.
用力地眨眼 用力眨眼 用力做三次
Hard, press them hard, thrice.
用力 用力眨眼 三次
Alright?
好了嗎
Not yet? It will come. It will work out.
還沒有 它會有感覺的 會起作用的
Watch me, watch me here.
看著我 看著我
Please take the baby out a little bit, because everybody tries to meditate.
請帶寶寶離開一下 因為每個人都在冥想
Alright, just for a minute
好吧 就幾分鐘 就一會兒
Don’t feel guilty, none of you should feel guilty.
不要感到內疚 你們誰也不應該感到內疚
Everybody has certain problems still. You just go and say:
每個人都有某些問題 你只要去說
Mother I am not guilty. Close your eyes, just close your eyes.
母親 我毫無內疚 閉上眼睛 閉上眼睛
There is nothing to feel guilty about anything whatsoever.
無論任何事情都不必感到內疚
Whatever you have done is finished now.
無論你做過什麼 現在都結束了
You are entering into new awareness now. Into the kingdom of God.
你現在正在進入全新的意識 進入上帝的國度
Now you have become the spirit, and spirit cannot be guilty.
現在你已經成為了靈 而靈是不會內疚的
Forget about the people who have not come today with you. Anyone.
忘記今天沒有和你一起來的任何人
Just forget them. Just start to be yourself.
忘了他們吧 開始做你自己吧
They can come later on and you can give them the full advantage.
他們可以晚點來 你可以給到他們全部的好處
Those who have got liver problem should take sugar
那些有肝臟問題的人應該吃糖
and they’ll tell you what is to be done.
他們會告訴你該怎麼做
If you have diabetes you can take salt.
如果你有糖尿病 你必須吃鹽
And for other people who have arthritis and all that also,
對於那些患有關節炎的人
I’ll ask you to bring some petrol or kerosene on,
請帶一些汽油或煤油來
if not you can come back again and take it from these.
如果沒有 下次過來的時候 可以從這些人那裡拿一些
Thank you very much. Enjoy your life.
非常感謝 享受午餐吧
May God bless you!
願神祝福你們